A Guide to the Edward Lawrie Tatum papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA133
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1946 1948-1975; 2
  - H-I
    - Holiday, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Holz, G.G., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Horn, G. At RI, 1957-1965; 8 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Houghton Mifflin Co., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hug, G., 5 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Indiana University, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Institute for Scientific Information. E.L. Tatum becomes member of Science Citation Index editorial advisory board, 1969 November; 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Harmon, J.A. Stanford student, 1949-1959 1970; 51 letters (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - International Foundation for Molecular Biology. E.L. Tatum founding member and a director of the corporation of the, 32 letters (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - J-K
    - Jackson, G.J., 9 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jacobson, C., 6 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jaffe, H., 7 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jefferson Hotel, 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jones, A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jones, D., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kabisch, W.T., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kacser, H., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kelley, R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kendrick, J., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kent, M., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kert, L.A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - King, J.A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - King, Martin Luther, 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes telegram from New York City Nobel Laureates in Science on King assassination.
    - Kinsky, S.C. At RI, 1962 May-August; 21 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Klingmüller, W., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Koch, E.R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Köller, K-H In German, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Koprowski, H., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Krieghbaum, H. Comments on science reporting, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Krim, A.B., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Kunitz, M. Biographical note by E.L. Tatum, 1964 December; 10 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Includes working material. similar biographical. note by E.L. Tatum for nomination for election to NAS.
    - Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1957-1958 1969-1973; 19 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
      E.L. Tatum member of editorial board of JBC and member of publications committee from.
  - L-Lu
    - Landman, O.E., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lapira, G., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lara, F., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Latka, L. Comments on reading books, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Law, L.L., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lerner, C., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Life, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Life Sciences, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lockhart, J.D., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Long Island University, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Luria, S.E., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lanni, F., 36 letters (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lederberg, Esther, 1956 1968 1971; 6 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lederberg, Joshua 1951-1975. Letter, 1972 October 13; 99 letters (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Tatum to Lederberg states that in move to Stanford and then to RU correspondence discarded.
    - Los Angeles Children's Hospital becomes member of research advisory council of Children's Hospital of Los Angeles [E.L. Tatum maintained file under: Los Angeles Children's Hospital], 1964 October; 36 letters (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - M-My
    - McClain, M.E., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - McGrady, C., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - McKusick, V.A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mankowski, T., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Marks, S., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Marmur, J., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Marquette University, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Marquis, A.N. Co., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Matthysse, A.G., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Moe, H.A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Morita, Y., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Murthy, M.R.V., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Muth, W., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mycopathologia et Mycologia Applicata, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Mach, Bernard. RU graduate student, 1961-1973; 59 letters (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Includes E.L. Tatum's presentation for degree granting and items on Moscow, IX Int'l Congress for Microbiology. [Indications are B. Mach presents paper by Mach and Tatum]. 1966 July 24-30.
    - Mahadavan, P.R. (ca. 1 inch). At RI, 1962-1965; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - 1962-1967 April (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - 1967 October-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Menaker, W. About possible election of Wm. H. Welch to Hall of Fame of Great Americans, 1960; 62 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Includes statement by Tatum and other Nobel Laureates in support of Welch.
    - Mercy Institute of Biomedical Research. E.L. Tatum becomes member of Advisory Board of, circa 1971 November; 25 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Miller, J.H. Stanford student, 1952-1958 1967; 23 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - N-Ni
    - Nakamura, K., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nakayama, M., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nature, 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nerio, K., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - New York Scientist's Committee for Public Information, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - New York Times Magazine Congratulations on L. Galton's article, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nickerson, W.J., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nightingale, E.O., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nading, L.K. RU graduate student, 27 letters (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Newmeyer, D.L. Yale, Stanford student, 1951-1955 1962; 18 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Niu, Man-Ching (ca. 2 inches) At RI ca. 1959 and RU, 1970 January-June; 3 folders (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - 1956 1959-1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - 1965-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Niu-Segal symposium "The role of DNA in reproduction and development" in 1972. Corres primarily with Niu about E.L. Tatum as editorial advisor getting symposium papers ready for publication by North Holland. Published in 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - O-Ov
    - Olds, P., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Oliver Wendell Holmes Association, 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Ottey, L.J. At Stanford, 1955-1956; 23 letters (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Overholt, Kay, 6 letters (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Ottke, R.C. Yale student and at Stanford, 1950-1951; 30 letters (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Includes items on Lucio Rodriquez, 1950-1953; 1957-1963.
  - P-Pr
    - Packard, Vance, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Papazian, H., 7 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Papier, L.S., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Pauling, Linus, 7 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Perish, J. Mrs, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Perry, J., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Peters, J.A., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Phalares, J., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Pilgeram, L.O., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Pittman, D., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Plaza Hotel, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Pomerat, G.R. About AIBS, 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Prinzmetal, M., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Perkins, D.D., 1960-1972; 17 letters (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine In. E.L. Tatum becomes member of advisory board of, 1964 January; 34 letters (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Pina, E. At RI, 1963-1974 1964-1966; 73 letters (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Pincheira, G. At RU, 1966-1973 1967-1969; 27 letters (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Quadri-Science, Inc., 1964 October 22; 37 letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Gaps in correspondence. Includes Tatum press conference in name of 33 Nobel Prize recipients supporting Humphrey-Johnson candidacies.
  - R-Ru
    - Rasmussen, A.F., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Reddy, G.M., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Reed, C.I., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Reid, R.D., 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Rembrecht, H., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Robertson, M.G., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Rohlfing, D.L., 2 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Rosenberg, I., 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Rosenthal, P.N., 5 letters (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ruddle, F.H., 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Ruffilli, D., 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Russell, E.S., 1 letter (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Rand, J. RU graduate student, 11 letters (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Rawson, R.W. About Explorer Science Camps, 17 letters (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Ray, Dixie Lee (ca. 1 inch) Report of a 6 month study, Dixie Lee Ray served as special assistant to Associate Director of Administration, (Paul A. Scherer) analyzing procedures and progress of NSF using National Center for Atmospheric Research as a case study; also Commission on Science and Technology and grant programs. Some handwritten notes to E.L. Tatum who asked to read reports, 1962 December-1963 May (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Reaume, Sheldon E. Yale student, 48 letters (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Reich, Edward (ca. 1-1/2 inches) RU graduate student and RU Faculty, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - 1962-1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Roboz-Einstein, E.. At Stanford, 1946-1962 1949-1951; 62 letters (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Rogers, Dexter. At Stanford, 1953-1961 1954-1955; 37 letters (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Ryan, Francis J., 1964 April 3; 13 letters (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Includes statement in memory of F.J. Ryan.
  - S-Sz
    - Saxena, M.P., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Schearer, S.B., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Schmitt, F.O., 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Schneider, M.J., 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Schorer, A.R., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Schwarz Bioresearch, 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Scientific Products, 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Selye, Hans, 1960 1964 1972; 12 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Includes comments on Selye ms with ms.
    - Shepard, M., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Shockley, W., 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Shook, W.I., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Silberman, A., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Singleton, W.R., 3 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Smith, E. L, 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sokel, S., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Solomon, B., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stanhope, W.W., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Steere, W.C., 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sterling, J.E.W., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Steuerwald, J., 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stickle, G., 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stickle, M., 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stoffel, W., 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stokes, S., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Stuyvesant Alumni and Scholarship Association, 1 letter (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Suski, K., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Suzuki, I., 4 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Szilard, L., 2 letters (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Salk East of Salk Institute Member of New York Scholars Group of, 6 letters (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Schiller, H.A., 62 letters (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Scott, W.A. At RU, 1967-1975; 33 letters (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Shanmugasundaram, E.R.B., 36 letters (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Includes items with/ about K. Radha, student and wife of.
    - Shatkin, A. (ca. 1 inch). RU graduate student, 1958-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Shemin, David, 1955-1971; 20 letters (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Sherwood, W.K. Stanford student, 57 letters (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Shockley, T.E. At RI, 1959-1967 1959-1961; 43 letters (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Silagi. Selma. At RU, 1962-1974 1962-1966; 55 letters (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Simmonds, S., 1958-1969; 63 letters (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Slayman, Clifford and Carolyn Walch. RU graduate students, 1960-1970; 48 letters (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Steere, W.C., 11 letters (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Includes copy of Chapter 8 "Structure of the genetic material and the concept of the gene" by G.W. Beadle for "This is life".
    - Strominger, J.L. About consideration of Strominger appointment as Professor of biochemistry at Harvard, 36 letters (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Szabo, G. Visiting Professor at RU from, 1971 September-1972 July; 36 letters (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - T-Tw
    - Tanaka, H., 4 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Tapley, D.F. At RU, 1965 October-1966 March; 5 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Temmen, L., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Terman, F., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Thomas, J., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Tilley, R.J., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Toole, J.V., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Torres, H.N., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Touster, O., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Towers, J.W. & Co., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Trugler, R., 2 letters (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Turian, G., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Turner, T.B., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Twitty, V.C., 1 letter (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Tanenbaum, S.W. At Stanford, 1950-1972 1951-1953; 59 letters (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Tomasz, Alexander RU Professor, 21 letters (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Tsuda, S. (ca. 1 inch). At RU, 1958-1971 1959-1962 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - U-V Miscellaneous
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 9 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - University of Miami, 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Upjohn Co., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Urban, R.G., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Vail Village Inn, 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - van Niel, C.B., 8 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Villarreal, C.G., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Vogel, H.J., 5 letters (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - University of Virginia E.L. Tatum member of Center for Advanced Studies scientific advisory board of, 1965-1974; 39 letters (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - University of Wisconsin Alumni Club of New York, 38 letters (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - van Wagtendonk, W.J., 1952-1971; 40 letters (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - W, Y, Z, Miscellaneous
    - Waelsch, S.G., 6 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wagner, R.P., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wainwright, S.D., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Walt Disney Productions, 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Warkany, J., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Weaver, Warren, 19 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Welch, A.D., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wells Fargo Bank, 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Western Union, 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Williams, R.J., 3 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Williams, R.P., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Winter, R., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wolf, B., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wolk, P., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wood, D., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Woodruff, H.G., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wooldridge, D.E., 2 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wulff, D.L., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Yahraes, H., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Zamecnik, P.C., 1 letter (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Zelan, B., 11 letters (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wilson, J.F. (ca. 1 inch). Stanford student, 1956-1974 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Wood, H.N. RU Faculty, 33 letters (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Wrathall, C.R. At RU, 1970-1974; 49 letters (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Yale University Concerning program in molecular biology at Yale, 5 letters (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Yanofsky, C., 1956-1966; 35 letters (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Zinder, N.D. RU Professor, 15 letters (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Letters of recommendation, (circa 2 inches) 3 folders
    Arranged in alphabetical order. Filed mainly by correspondent.
    - A-F (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - G-P (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - R-Z (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Questions from laity with replies, 1960-1965; 12 letters (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified (no last names), 6 letters (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Subject Files, 3
  These files consist of correspondence: plans: meetings (papers delivered at some); working material; reports; statements; petition and manuscript reviews functioning as scientific advisor (sometimes chairman); Board of Trustees (sometimes chairman); on editorial board or society member and consultant. Includes a 2-1/2 inch manuscript box dealing with Neurospora.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by society, institution, government agency or publication involved.
  - American Cancer Society (Scientific Advisory Council), 1956 July-1959 August (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - American Cancer Society (Advisory Committee on Personnel For Research), 1963 September-1966 August (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - American Philosophical Society. (APS), 1957-1971; 4 folders
    - 1957-1961 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1962-1967 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1968-1971, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Edsall grant. E.L. Tatum as member of APS council approves $5,000 grant to John T. Edsall for proposed study on the history of biochemistry and molecular biology (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ANNUAL REVIEW OF GENETICS, 1965-1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - BIOCHIMICA ET BIOPHYSICA ACTA, 1959-1973; 3 folders (Box 15)
    - 1959-1966 March (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1966 April-December (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1967-1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Children's Hospital Research Foundation, 1963-1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - City of Hope Medical Center, 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratories of Quantitative Biology, 1961-1968
    Covers the development of the Laboratories from its beginning as Long Island Biological Laboratory and Carnegie Institution of Washington and its financial support. In 5 folders.
    - 1961-1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1965-1966 June (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1966 July-October (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1966 November-1967 March (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1967 April-September 1968 November (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - FRONTIERS OF BIOLOGY, 1963-1970 1973-1975
    File consists primarily of original and photocopied correspondence (as co-editor with Neuberger of FRONTIERS OF BIOLOGY series) with various correspondents of North-Holland Publishing and contributors. In 8 folders:.
    - 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1965 January-August (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1965 September-December (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1966 January-August (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1966 September-1967 February (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - 1967 March-December (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1970 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Fungal Genetics Stock Center (FGSC), 1966-1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Related Materials
    See also under: Neurospora file in box no. 25.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Anne Hamill deposited it with RU Archives on June 10, 1976. Some items after E.L. Tatum's death.
    Editor's note. This file consists primarily of culture requests.
  - GENETICS, 1963-1968 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Grant and fellowship reviews, 1956-1975
    For various institutions. Includes:.
    - American Cancer Society
    - Guggenheim Foundation
    - NIH
    - NSF
    - Research Corporation
    - 1956-1963 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1964-1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Harvey Society (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - International Science Exhibition, Brussels 1958, 1958 October (Box 19, Folder 4)
    [See: Package for U.S. Dept. of State citation].
  - Jackson Laboratory, 1964-1975; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 1967-1970 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - McGRAW-HILL ENCYCLOPEDIA OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, 1957-1973; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1959-1965 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Massachusetts General Hospital (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mead Johnson & Co. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Merck, Sharp and Dohme, 1957-1970 1975 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Includes:.
    - Joint dedication of new research laboratories with Columbia P&S, 1966 May
    - Address "Molecular biology, nucleic acids and the future of medicine". Published in PERSPECTIVES IN BIOLOGY AND MEDICINE 10 (1966) 19-31
      Includes notes of address. [See: Film reel #2 for kinescope reproduction of dedication].
  - Muscular Dystrophy Associations of America (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1957-1975 (Box 21)
    Scope and Contents
    File consists primarily of balloting and biographical sketches prepared for proposed members. Includes recommendation of George Beadle and Don Hornig for NAS Presidency. In 3 folders.
    - 1957-1962 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1963-1967 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1968-1975 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - NAS and NAS-NRC Committees (E.L. Tatum member of), 1957-1971 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Includes: NAS-NRC Committees.
    - Committee on developmental biology (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Space Science Board committee (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Evaluating committee in life science for NSF postdoctoral fellowships (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Committee for the survey of chemistry (panel) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Advisory Committee to the Federal Radiation Council NAS Committee (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Committee of the U.S. Steel Foundation Award in Molecular Biology (Chairman in), 1971 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - PROCEEDINGS OF THE NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES (PNAS), 4 folders (Box 22)
    Includes some mss reviewed by Tatum and others.
    - 1963-1967 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1968 February-November (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 1968 November-1970 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - National Foundation (NF) formerly National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (NFIP), 1954 1957-1975 (Box 23)
    Includes 1958 research report (published in 1963); papers delivered at various NF committees meetings and conferences sponsored by NF. Some published. In 10 folders:.
    - 1954 1957-1959 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1960-1975 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - NF meeting and conferences sponsored by NF E.L. Tatum attended or involved in (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - NYC RI, NF meeting, 1959 September 23 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Geneva, 4th International Poliomyelitis Conference (IPC), 1957 July 8-12 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - London, 1st Intl Conference on Congenital Malformations, 1960 July 18-22; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - 1959 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Tatum presents "Some molecular aspects of congenital malformations" Published In: International Conferences on Congenital Malformations. 1st, London, 1960. Philadelphia, Lippincott, 1961. pp. 281-288, 1960 July 22 (Box 23, Folder 6)
        [#116 in Tatum bibliography - reprint lacking in bound volume of collected reprints]. Includes various copies of ms.
    - Copenhagen, 5th International Poliomyelitis Congress, 1960 July 26-28 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Los Angeles, 1st Inter-American Conference on Congenital Defects, 1962 January 22-24 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - NYC 2nd International Conference on Congenital Malformations, 1963 July 14-19 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Hague, Netherlands 3rd Intl Conference on Congenital Malformations, 1969 September 8-12 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - National Institutes of Health (NIH) Genetics Study Section, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - 1957-1964 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1965-1966 1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - NIH Research Training Grant Committee (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - National Science Foundation-National Science Board (NSF-NSB), 1957-1968 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    Includes 2 group photographs taken at NSB meetings: (some identified) [nd] 1957 March 11.
    [See 1957 Mar 11 photograph for some identification].
  - NSF-NSB Ad-Hoc Committee on Faculty Salaries (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - NSF/AID (AGENCY FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT) Program in India (trip), 1966 May (Box 24, Folder 6)
    1-5 trip to India to develop science education program.
  - Neurospora, 1950-1972 1975 (Box 25)
    Primarily culture requests and other miscellaneous items concerning Neurospora
    - Arrangement of Neurospora information from E.L. Tatum Laboratory
      [See also under: Ray Barratt in box no. 4; Laura Garnjobst in box no. 6; D.D. Perkins in box no. 13 and FGSC in box no. 18]. In 4 folders:.